<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f032_intentions1894"><body><div change="#StB" n="31" type="r"><sp who="#C."><p><pb facs="#f032"/> <milestone facs="#f032_z000" n="31" unit="folio_number"/> <lb/> <note facs="#f032_z002" rend="pencil">Type-setter's signature: Davis</note> <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><milestone facs="#f032_z001" unit="bracket"/><hi change="#StB" hand="#Wilde" rend="underline">V</hi><hi rend="underline">.</hi><hi rend="italic">ivian</hi>. My dear fellow, whatever you<lb/> may say, it is merely a dramatic<lb/> utterance, and no more represents<lb/> Shakespeare's real views upon Art<lb/> than the speeches of Iago represent<lb/> his real views upon morals. But<lb/> let me get to the end of the<lb/> passage: <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p>"Art finds her own perfection within,<lb/> and not <milestone facs="#f032_z008" unit="caret"/>outside of, herself. She is not to<lb/> be judged by any external standard <lb/>of resemblance. She is a <lb/>veil, rather than a mirror. She has <lb/>flowers that no forests know of,<lb/> birds that no woodland possesses. She<lb/> makes and unmakes<milestone n="nc_47"/> many worlds, and<lb/> can draw the moon from <del change="#StE" facs="#f032_z014" hand="#Wilde">the </del>heaven with<lb/> a scarlet thread. Hers are the 'forms<lb/> more real than living man,' and hers<lb/> the great archetypes of which things<lb/> that<milestone facs="#f032_z017" unit="x"/> have existence are but unfinished copies.<lb/> Nature has, in her eyes, no laws, no<lb/> uniformity. She can work miracles at<lb/> her will, and when she calls monsters<lb/><milestone n="intentions_26"/> from the deep they come. She can bid <lb/>the almondtree blossom in winter, and <lb/>send the snow upon the ripe cornfield.<lb/> At her word the frost lays its silver<lb/> finger on the burning mouth of June,<lb/> and the winged lions creep out from<lb/> the hollows of the Lydian hills. The</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>