<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f029_diplo">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="28" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f029"/><milestone facs="#f029_z000" n="28" unit="folio_number"/><note facs="#f029_z001" rend="pencil">Typesetter's signature: Hendra. Bracket signaling either new paragraph or beginning of new typesetter's section.</note><lb/><milestone facs="#f029_z001" unit="bracket"/><hi change="#StB" facs="#f029_z002" hand="#Wilde" rend="underline">Vivian</hi>. I assure you it is quite true , and the amusing part of the whole<lb/> thing is that the story of the cherry<lb/>tree is an absolute myth. However <lb/>you must not think that I am<lb/> too despondent about the <add change="#StBa" facs="#f029_z004" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="caret">artistc </add><milestone facs="#f029_z004" unit="caret"/>future <lb/>of America or of our own country. Listen<lb/> to this.<lb/></p>
					<p>"That some change will take place<lb/> before this century has drawn to its<lb/> close, we have no doubt whatsoever.<lb/> Bored by the tedious and improving <lb/>conversation of those who have neither<lb/> the wit to exaggerate nor the <del change="#StBa" facs="#f029_z008" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">genius </del><lb/>genius to romance, tired of the<lb/> intelligent person whose reminiscences<lb/> are always based upon memory, whose<lb/> statements are invariably limited by<lb/> probability, and who is at any time<lb/> liable to be corroborated by the<lb/> merest Philistine who happens to be <lb/>present, Society sooner or later must <lb/>return to its lost leader<del change="#StB" hand="#Wilde">,</del> the cultured<lb/> and fascinating liar. Who he was<lb/> who first<del change="#StB" hand="#Wilde">,</del> without ever having gone<lb/> out to the rude chase<del change="#StB" hand="#Wilde">,</del> told the <lb/>wondering cave-men at sunset how he <lb/><del change="#StAb" facs="#f029_z011" hand="#Wilde">had slain </del><lb/><del change="#StAb" facs="#f029_z011" hand="#Wilde">the Mammoth in single combat and</del><lb/><del change="#StAb" facs="#f029_z011" hand="#Wilde"> brought back his gilded tusks, or</del><lb/><del change="#StAb" facs="#f029_z011" hand="#Wilde"> dragged the Megatherim form the purple</del><lb/><del change="#StAb" facs="#f029_z011" hand="#Wilde"> darkness of her jasper cave.</del> had dragged the Megatherium from <del change="#StBa" facs="#f029_z010" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">its </del><lb/>the purple darkness of its jasper<lb/> cave, or slain the Mammoth in<lb/> single combat and brought back its golden <del change="#StBa" facs="#f029_z012" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">claws </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f029_z013" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="no_caret">tusks</add>, -- we cannot tell, and<lb/> not one of our <milestone n="nc_46"/>modern<milestone n="intentions_24"/>anthropologists</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>