<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio53_intentions1894">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="54" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f055"/><milestone facs="#f055_z000" n="53" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>from the art of a time to the time<lb/> itself is the great mistake that all<lb/> historians commit. <lb/></p>
					<p>The second doctrine is this. All bad<lb/> art comes from returning to Life<lb/> and Nature, and elevating them<lb/> into ideals. Life and Nature may <milestone facs="#f055_z007" unit="caret"/>sometimes be<lb/> used as part of A<add>rt's</add> <milestone facs="#f055_z008" unit="caret"/>rough material, but before<lb/> they are of any real service to Art<lb/> they must be translated into artistic <lb/>conventions. The moment Art surrenders<lb/> its imaginative medium it surrenders<lb/> everything. As a method Realism<lb/> is a complete failure, and the two<lb/> things that every artist should avoid<lb/> are modernity of form and modernity <lb/>of subject-matter. To us, who live in<lb/> the nineteenth century, any century is<lb/> a suitable subject for art except<lb/> our own. The only beautiful things are<lb/> the things that do not concern us. It is, to<lb/> have the pleasure of quoting myself, exactly<lb/> because Hecuba is nothing to us that<lb/> her sorrows are so suitable a motive for<lb/> a tragedy.<lb/> Besides, it is only the modern that ever <lb/>becomes old-fashioned. M. Zola sits down<lb/> to give us a picture of the Second Empire. <lb/>Who cares for the Second Empire now?<lb/> It is out of date. Life goes faster than Realism,<lb/> but Romanticism is always in front of Life. <lb/></p>
					<p>The third doctrine is that Life<lb/> imitates Art far more than Art <lb/>imitates Life. This results not merely<lb/> from Life's imitative instinct, but<lb/> from the fact that the self-conscious aim of Life<lb/> is to find expression, and that<lb/> Art<milestone n="intentions_45"/> offers it certain beautiful forms<lb/> through which it may realize that energy.</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>