<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f051_intentions1891">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="50" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f051"/><milestone facs="#f051_z000" n="49" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>afternoon teas. But this is <lb/>merely the light and graceful side of<lb/> lying, such as was probably heard at <lb/>Cretan dinner parties. There are many <lb/>other forms. Lying for the sake of <lb/>gaining some immediate personal <lb/>advantage, <milestone facs="#f051_z003" unit="enclosure"/><milestone facs="#f051_z003" unit="caret"/>for instance--lying with a moral purpose, as it is usually called--though of late<lb/> it has been <milestone n="nc_54"/>rather looked down upon, was<lb/> extremely popular with the antique world. <lb/>Athena laughs when Odysseus tells her<lb/> <add change="#StD" facs="#f051_z007" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">'his words of sly devising,' as Mr William Morris phrases it, </add><lb/> <del change="#StD" facs="#f051_z007" hand="#Wilde">what a Cambridge Professor<milestone facs="#f051_z006" unit="caret"/>once elegantly<lb/> termed a 'whopper,'</del> and the glory of<lb/> mendacity illumines the pale brow of <lb/>the stainless hero of Euripidean <lb/>tragedy, and sets among the noble <lb/>women of the past the young bride of one of <lb/>Horace's most exquisite odes. Later on, what <milestone facs="#f051_z008" unit="caret"/>at first had been merely a natural instinct<lb/> was elevated into a <milestone facs="#f051_z009" unit="guiding_line"/>self-conscious <milestone facs="#f051_z009 #f051_z010" unit="caret"/>science. Elaborate<lb/> rules were laid down for the guidance<lb/> of mankind, and an important <lb/>school of literature grew up round the <lb/>subject. Indeed, when one remembers the <lb/>excellent philosophical treatise of<lb/> Sanchez on the whole question, one cannot help <lb/>regretting that no one has ever thought of <lb/>publishing a cheap and <milestone n="institutions_42"/>condensed edition <lb/>of the works of that great casuist.<lb/> A short primer, <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">"</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">'</add>When to Lie and <del change="#StD" facs="#f051_z025" hand="#comp">h</del><add change="#StD" facs="#f051_z025" hand="#comp" place="intentions">H</add>ow,<del change="#StD" hand="#comp">"</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">'</add> <lb/>if brought out in an attractive and<lb/> not too expensive <milestone facs="#f051_z023" unit="caret"/>a form, would<milestone facs="#f051_z021" unit="caret"/> no doubt command a large sale, and would prove of</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>