<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f022_intentions1894">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="21" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f022"/><milestone facs="#f022_z000" n="21" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>and the address to Mr Wilkinson's spade. <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#C.">
					<p><hi change="#StB" hand="#Wilde" rend="underline">C</hi><hi rend="italic">yril</hi>. I think that view might be <lb/>questioned. I am rather inclined to<lb/> believe in the "impulse from a vernal <lb/>wood," though of course the artistic<lb/> value of such an impulse depends<lb/> entirely on the kind of temperament<lb/> that receives it, so that the return to Nature would come to mean simply the advance to a great personality. You would agree with that, I fancy. However, proceed with<lb/> your article.</p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><hi change="#StB" hand="#Wilde" rend="underline">V</hi><hi rend="italic">ivian</hi> (<hi change="#StB" rend="italic">reading</hi>). "Art begins with abstract <lb/>decoration with purely imaginative and <lb/>pleasurable work dealing with what is <lb/>unreal and non-existent. This is the<lb/> first stage. Then Life becomes fascinated<lb/> with this new wonder, and asks to be <lb/>admitted into the charmed [<hi change="#StC" facs="#f022_z006" rend="small">9</hi><milestone n="nc_43"/>circle. Art <lb/>takes life as part of her rough material,<lb/> recreates it, and refashions it in<lb/> fresh forms, is absolutely indifferent<lb/> to fact, invents, imagines, dreams, and<lb/> keeps between herself and reality the <lb/>impenetrable barrier of beautiful style,<lb/> of decorative or ideal treatment. The<lb/> third stage is when Life gets the<lb/> upper hand, and drives Art out into the <lb/>wilderness. This is the true decadence, and <lb/>it is from this that we are now<lb/> suffering.</p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p>"Take the case of the English <lb/>drama. At first in the hands of the <lb/>monks Dramatic Art was abstract, decorative, <add change="#StE" facs="#f022_z012" place="intentions_1894">and </add><lb/>mythological. Then she enlisted<lb/>Life in her service, and using some of</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>