<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio09_diplo">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="9" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f010"/><milestone facs="#f010_z000" n="9" unit="folio_number"/><lb/><note facs="#f010_z001" rend="pencil">Typesetter signature, "Bradley" in pencil</note>contradicting people who are much younger<lb/> than himself, and often ends by writing<lb/> novels which are so like Life that<lb/>no <del change="#StAb" facs="#f010_z005" hand="#Wilde">body </del><add change="#StB" facs="#f010_z004" hand="#Wilde" place="inspace">one</add> can possibly believe them. This<lb/> is no isolated instance that we are<lb/> giving. It is simply one example out<lb/> of many; and if something cannot be<lb/> done to check, or at least to modify,<lb/> our monstrous worship of facts<add change="#StB" hand="#Wilde" place="inspace">,</add> Art<lb/> will become sterile, and Beauty will<lb/> pass away from the land."<lb/></p>
					<p>"Even Mr. Robert Louis Stevenson,<lb/> that exquisite master of delicate and<lb/> fanciful prose, <del change="#StAb" facs="#f010_z010" hand="#Wilde">what we must call </del><add change="#StB" facs="#f010_z010" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">is tainted with</add> this<lb/> modern vice, for <del change="#StBb" facs="#f010_z011" hand="#Wilde" rend="pencil">there is </del><add change="#StBb" facs="#f010_z012" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="pencil">we </add><del change="#StAb" facs="#f010_z014" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">really </del><add change="#StAb" facs="#f010_z014" hand="#Wilde" place="above">positively </add><add change="#StBb" facs="#f010_z013" hand="#Wilde" place="inspace margin" rend="pencil">know </add><lb/>no other name for it. There is such<lb/> a thing as robbing a story of its<lb/> reality by trying to make it too true,<lb/> and '<hi change="#StC" rend="italic">The Black Arrow</hi>' is so inartistic<note>Serialized in 1883. Published as a book in 1888. As Guy notes, Wilde wrote to Ross from Reading Gaol, "complaining about the state of the prison library and suggesting that he might present thre authorities with 'a dozen good novels', including 'Stevenson (none here but the Black Arrow!)'" (Guy 367, quoting H &amp; H-D, 646, 790).</note><lb/><del change="#StAb" facs="#f010_z016" hand="#Wilde">it has not got</del> <add change="#StB" facs="#f010_z016" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">that it does not contain </add>a<lb/> single anachronism to boast of, while the<lb/> transformation of Dr. Jekyll reads<lb/> dangerously like an experiment<del change="#StAb" facs="#f010_z017" hand="#Wilde"> in</del> <add change="#StB" facs="#f010_z017" hand="#StB" place="inline">out of</add> <hi rend="underline">The </hi><add>the </add><hi change="#StB" rend="underline">Lancet</hi>. As for Mr Rider Haggard<lb/> who really has, or had once, the makings<lb/> of a perfectly magnificent liar, he<lb/> is now so afraid of being suspected of<lb/> genius that when he does tell us<lb/> anything marvellous<add change="#StB" facs="#f010_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">,</add> he feels bound<lb/> to invent a personal reminiscence, and<lb/> to put it into a footnote as a kind<note>Both Guy and Schroeder suggest that ilde was likely interested in the (accurate) accusations of plagiarism levied at Haggard in the Pall Mall Gazette. Guy and Schroeder both identify Haggard's novels Allan Quatermain and Maiwa's Revenge as the alluded to works containing footnotes. While Guy notes that footnotes contain "information. . .derived from Haggard's own inexperience of Africa," which would suggest the jab at their inclusion being to sere as "cowardly corroboration," Schroeder argues that many of the footnotes in Maiwa's Revenge are "mock-serious," and that "Wilde must have enjoyed [them] and. . .is here criticizing tongue-and-cheek" (Guy 367, Schroeder 29).</note><lb/> of cowardly corroboration. Nor are our<lb/> other novelists much better. Mr. Henry</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>