<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio27_diplo"><body><div change="#StB" n="27" type="r"><sp who="#V."><p><pb facs="#f028"/><milestone facs="#f028_z000" n="27" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>Benvenuto Cellini; in the memoirs of Casanuova ; in Defoe's '<hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic">History of the</hi><lb/><hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic"> Plague</hi>'; in Boswell's '<hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Life of Johnson</hi>';<lb/> in Napoleon's despatches, and in <lb/>the works of our own Carlyle whose<lb/> '<hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic">French Revolution</hi>' is one of the most <lb/>fascinating historical romances ever <lb/>written, facts are either kept in their<lb/> proper subordinate position, or else<lb/> entirely excluded on the general ground<lb/> of dullness. Now everything is changed. <lb/>Facts are not merely finding a footing<lb/> in history, but <del change="#StAb" facs="#f028_z010" hand="#Wilde">have usurpred</del><add change="#StB" facs="#f028_z010" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">they are usurping</add><lb/> the domain of Fancy, and have invaded<lb/> the kingdom of Romance. Their chilling <lb/>touch is over everything. They are <lb/>vulgarising mankind. The <del change="#StAb" facs="#f028_z011" hand="#Wilde">crude </del><add change="#StB" facs="#f028_z011" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">dull </add><lb/>commercial<milestone n="intentions_23"/>ism of America, its materialising<lb/> spirit, its indifference to the poetical<lb/> side of things, and its lack of imagination <lb/>and of high unattainable ideals<del change="#StB" facs="#f028_z012" hand="#Wilde">,</del> are <lb/>entirely due to that country having adopted<lb/> for its <del change="#StBa" facs="#f028_z015" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">hero </del>national hero<del change="#StB" facs="#f028_z013" hand="#Wilde">,</del> a man<del change="#StB" facs="#f028_z014" hand="#Wilde">,</del> who <lb/>according to his own confession was <lb/>incapable of telling a lie<del change="#StAb" facs="#f028_z017" hand="#Wilde">;</del><add change="#StB" facs="#f028_z017" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">,</add> and it is <lb/>not too much to say that the story of<lb/> George Washington and the cherry-tree <lb/>has done more harm, and in a shorter <lb/>space of time than any other moral tale<lb/> in the whole of literature." <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#C.">
					<p><hi change="#StB" facs="#f028_z001" rend="underline">Cyril.</hi>my dear boy!</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>