<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio47_intentions1891"><body><div change="#StB" n="47" type="r"><sp who="#V."><p><pb facs="#f048"/><milestone facs="#f048_z000" n="47" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>But read an authority, like Aristophanes<lb/> for instance. You will find that the<lb/> Athenian ladies laced tightly, wore<lb/> high-heeled shoes, dyed their hair<lb/> yellow, painted and rouged their faces,<lb/> and were exactly like any silly<lb/> fashionable or fallen creature of our<lb/> own day. The fact is that we look back on the<lb/> ages entirely through the medium<lb/> of Art, and Art, very fortunately, has <milestone facs="#f048_z003" unit="caret"/>never once told<lb/> us the truth.<lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#StC">
					<p><hi change="#StC" rend="italic">C</hi><del change="#StD" facs="#f031_z001" hand="#comp"><hi change="#StB">.</hi></del><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">yril.</hi></add><lb/>But modern portraits by English <lb/>painters, what of them? Surely they <lb/>are like the people they pretend to<lb/> represent? <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><hi change="#StC" rend="italic">V</hi><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">ivian</hi></add>. <lb/>Quite so. They are so like them<lb/> that a hundred years from<milestone n="nc_53"/> now no<lb/> one will believe in them. The <lb/>only portraits <del change="#StD" facs="#f048_z005" hand="#Wilde">that </del><add change="#StD" facs="#f048_z005" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">in which </add>one believes <del change="#StD" facs="#f048_z006" hand="#Wilde">in</del><lb/>are portraits where there is very little<lb/> of the sitter, and a <add change="#StD" facs="#f048_z008" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">very </add>great deal<lb/> of the artist. Holbein's <del change="#StD" facs="#f048_z009" hand="#Wilde">portaits </del><add change="#StD" facs="#f048_z009" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">drawings</add><milestone facs="#f048_z010" unit="enclosure"/><milestone facs="#f048_z010" unit="caret"/>of the men and women of his time <lb/>impress us with a sense of their absolute<lb/> reality. But this is simply because<lb/> Holbein compelled life to accept his<lb/> conditions, to restrain itself within his <lb/>limitations, to reproduce his type, and<lb/> to appear as he wished it to appear.<lb/> It is style that makes us believe in<lb/> a thing--nothing but style. Most</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>