<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio41_intentions1891"><body><div change="#StB" n="41" type="r"><sp who="#V."><p><pb facs="#f042"/><milestone facs="#f042_z000" n="41" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>However, I do not wish to dwell any<lb/> further upon individual instances. Personal<lb/><milestone facs="#f042_z002" unit="guiding_line"/> experience is a most vicious and limited circle. <lb/>All that I desire to point out is<lb/> the general principle that <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">l</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">L</add>ife imitates<lb/> <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">a</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">A</add>rt far more than <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">a</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">A</add>rt imitates <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">l</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">L</add>ife,<lb/> and I feel sure that if you think<lb/> seriously about it you will find<lb/> that it is true. <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">l</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">L</add>ife holds the mirror<lb/> up to <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">a</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">A</add>rt, and either reproduces some<lb/> strange type imagined by <milestone facs="#f042_z007" unit="guiding_line"/>painter or sculptor, or<lb/> realises in fact what has been<lb/> dreamed in fiction. Scientifically speaking,<lb/> the basis of life--the energy of life,<lb/> as Aristotle would call it--is simply<lb/> the desire for expression, and <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">a</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">A</add>rt is<lb/> always presenting various forms through<lb/> which this <milestone facs="#f042_z011" unit="caret"/>expression can be attained. <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">l</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">L</add>ife <lb/>seizes on them and uses them, even if <lb/>they be to her own hurt. Young men<lb/> have committed suicide because Rolla<lb/> did so, have<milestone n="intentions 32"/> died by their own hand<lb/> because by his own hand Werther died.<lb/> Think of what we owe to the<lb/> imitation of Christ, of what we owe<lb/> to the imitation of Cæsar. <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#C.">
					<p><hi change="#StB" hand="#Wilde" rend="underline">C</hi><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">yril</hi></add>. The theory is certainly a very <lb/>curious one<add change="#StD" facs="#f042_z017" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">, but to make it complete you must show that Nature, no less</add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f042_z017" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> than Life, is an imitation of Art. Are you prepared</add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f042_z017" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> to prove that?</add><lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">Vivian</hi>. My dear fellow, I am prepared to prove </add><lb/> <add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">anything.</add> <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#C.">
					<p><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">Cyril.</hi> Nature follows the landscape painter then, and </add><lb/> <add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">takes her effects from him? </add><lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">Vivian</hi></add>. <add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">Certainly. Where, if not from the Impressionists,</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> do we get those wonderful brown fogs that come creeping</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> down our streets, blurring the gas-lamps and changing</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> the houses into monstrous shadows? To whom, if not to </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">them and their master, do we owe the lovely silver mists</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> that brood over our river, and turn to faint forms of</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> fading grace curved bridge and swaying barge? The </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">extraordinary change that has taken place in the climate</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> of London during the last ten years is entirely due to</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> this particular school of Art. You smile. Consider the </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">matter from a scientific or a metaphysical point of view,</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> and you will find that I am right. For what is Nature?</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> Nature is no great mother who has borne us. She is our </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">creation. It is in our brain that she quickens to life.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> Things are because we see them, and what we see, and</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> how we see it, depends on the Arts that have influenced</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> us. To look at a thing is very different from seeing a</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> thing. One does not see anything until one sees its</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> beauty. Then, and then only, does it come into existence.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> At present, people see fogs, not because there</add><lb/><milestone n="intentions_35"/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> are fogs, but because poets and painters have taught </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">them the mysterious loveliness of such effects. There</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> may have been fogs for centuries in London. I dare say </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">there were. But no one saw them, and so we do not</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> know anything about them. They did not exist until</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> Art had invented them. Now, it must be admitted, fogs</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> are carried to excess. They have become the mere</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> mannerism of a clique, and the exaggerated realism of</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> their method gives dull people bronchitis. Where the</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> cultured catch an effect, the uncultured catch cold.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> And so, let us be humane, and invite Art to turn her</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> wonderful eyes elsewhere. She has done so already,</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> indeed. That white quivering sunlight that one sees</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> now in France, with its strange blotches of mauve, and </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">its restless violet shadows, is her latest fancy, and, on the</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> whole, Nature produces it quite admirably. Where she</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> used to give us Corots and Daubignys, she gives us now </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">exquisite Monets and entrancing Pisaros. Indeed there</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> are moments, rare, it is true, but still to be observed from</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> time to time, when Nature becomes absolutely modern. </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">Of course she is not always to be relied upon. The fact </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">is that she is in this unfortunate position. Art creates</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> an incomparable and unique effect, and, having done so,</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> passes on to other things. Nature, upon the other hand, </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">forgetting that imitation can be made the sincerest form</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> of insult, keeps on repeating this effect until we all </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">become absolutely wearied of it. Nobody of any real </add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">culture, for instance, ever talks nowadays about the</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> beauty of the sunset. Sunsets are quite old-fashioned.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> They belong to the time when Turner was the last note</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> in Art. To admire them is a distinct sign of provincialism</add><milestone n="intentions_51"/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> <lb/>of temperament. Upon the other hand, they go on.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> Yesterday evening Mrs. Arundel insisted on my going to</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> the window, and looking at the glorious sky, as she called</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> it. Of course, I had to look at it. She is one of those</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> absurdly pretty Philistines, to whom one can deny</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> nothing. And what was it? It was simply a very</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> second-rate Turner, a Turner of a bad period, with all</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> the painter's worst faults exaggerated and over-emphasized.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> Of course, I am quite ready to admit that Life</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> very often commits the same error. She produces her</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> false Renés and her sham Vautrins, just as Nature gives</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> us, on one day a doubtful Cuyp, and on another a more</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> than questionable Rousseau. Still, Nature irritates one</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> more when she does things of that kind. It seems so</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> stupid, so obvious, so unnecessary. A false Vautrin</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> might be delightful. A doubtful Cuyp is unbearable.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> However, I don't want to be too hard on Nature. I wish</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> the Channel, especially at Hastings, did not look quite</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> so often like a Henry Moore, grey pearl with yellow</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> lights, but then, when Art is more varied, Nature will,</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> no doubt, be more varied also. That she imitates Art,</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> I don't think even her worst enemy would deny now.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> It is the one thing that keeps her in touch with civilized</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> man. But have I proved my theory to your satisfaction. </add><lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#C.">
					<p><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">Cyril</hi>. You have proved it to my dissatisfaction, which</add><lb/><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> is better.</add> But even<lb/> admitting this strange imitative<lb/> instinct in <del change="#StD" hand="#comp">l</del><add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">L</add>ife, surely you would <lb/>acknowledge that art expresses the</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>