<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio34_diplo">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="34" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f035"/><milestone facs="#f035_z000" n="34" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>Apollo, that she might bear children <lb/>as lovely as the works of art that she <lb/>looked at in her rapture or her pain. They knew that <del change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z001" hand="#Wilde" rend="multi-stroke">Art </del>L<add change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z001" hand="#Wilde" place="right margin inline" rend="no_caret">ife </add><lb/>gains from <del change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z002" hand="#Wilde" rend="multi-stroke">Life </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z002" hand="#Wilde" place="inline" rend="no_caret">A</add><add change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z002" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">rt </add>not merely <lb/>spirituality, depth of thought and<lb/>passion , soul-turmoil or soul-peace,<lb/> but that she can<milestone n="nc_48"/> form herself on<lb/> the very lines and colours of Art, and<lb/> can reproduce the dignity of Pheidias<lb/> as well as the grace of Praxiteles. Hence<lb/> came their objection to Realism. They<lb/> disliked it on purely social grounds. They<lb/> felt that it inevitably makes people <lb/>ugly, and they were perfectly right. We<lb/> try to improve the <del change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z006" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">beauty </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z007" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="no_caret">condition</add> of the race<lb/> by means of good air, free sunlight, wholesome<lb/> water, and hideous bare buildings for<lb/> the better housing of the <del change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z008" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">lower classes </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f035_z009" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="no_caret">people </add>.<lb/> But these things merely produce health,<lb/> they do not produce beauty. For this,<lb/> <add change="#StB" facs="#f035_z010" hand="#Wilde" place="overwritten">A</add>rt is required, and the true disciples<lb/> of the great artist, are not his<lb/> studio-imitators, but those who become<lb/> like his works of art, be they plastic as in<lb/><milestone n="intentions_28"/>Greek days, or pictorial as in <lb/>modern times. <add change="#StBb" facs="#f035_z012" hand="#Wilde" place="above inline left" rend="pencil_caret">In fact, </add><milestone facs="#f035_z012" unit="caret"/>Life is Art's best, Art's only<lb/> pupil.<lb/></p>
					<p>As it is with the visible arts, so<lb/> it is with literature. The most obvious<lb/> and the vulgarest form in which this<lb/> is shown is in the case of the silly<lb/> boys who after reading the adventures<lb/> of Jack Sheppard or Dick Turpin, pillage</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>