<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f023_nc">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="22" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f023"/><milestone facs="#f023_z000" n="21" unit="folio_number"/><lb/><add change="#StC" facs="#f023_z001" hand="#comp" place="nc">l</add><del change="#StC" facs="#f023_z001" hand="#comp">L</del>ife's external forms, she created an <lb/>entirely new race of beings, whose <lb/>sorrows were more<milestone n="intentions_19"/>terrible than any <lb/>sorrow man has ever felt, whose joys <lb/>were keener than lover<add change="#StC" facs="#f023_z002" hand="#comp" place="nc">'</add>s<del change="#StC" facs="#f023_z002" hand="#comp">'</del> joys, who had <lb/>the rage of the Titans and the calm<lb/> of the <add change="#StC" facs="#f023_z003" hand="#comp" place="nc">g</add><del change="#StC" facs="#f023_z003" hand="#comp">G</del>ods, who had monstrous and<lb/> marvellous sins, monstrous and <lb/>marvellous virtues. To them she gave <lb/>a language different from that of <lb/>actual life , a language full of <lb/>resonant music and sweet rhythm, made <lb/>stately by solemn cadence<add change="#StC" facs="#f023_z005" hand="#comp" place="nc">,</add> or made<lb/> delicate by fanciful rhyme, jewelled<lb/> with wonderful words, and enriched with <lb/>lofty diction. She clothed her children<lb/> in strange raiment and gave them <lb/>masks, and at her bidding the antique <lb/>world rose from its marble tomb. A <lb/>new Cæsar passed through the streets<lb/> of risen Rome, and with purple sail <lb/>and flute-led oars another Cleopatra floated <lb/>down <add change="#StB" facs="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="inspace">the river</add> to Antioch. Old myth<del change="#StC" facs="#f023_z010" hand="#comp">,</del> and legend<del change="#StC" facs="#f023_z011" hand="#comp">,</del> <lb/>and dream took shape and substance. History <lb/>was entirely re-written, and <add change="#StB" facs="#f023_z013" hand="#Wilde" place="inspace">there was not </add><add change="#StB" facs="#f023_z014" hand="#Wilde" place="inspace"><lb/>one of the dramatists</add> who did not recognize<lb/> that <hi change="#StC" facs="#f023_z017" rend="italic">the object of art is not simple</hi><lb/><hi rend="italic"> truth but complex </hi><add change="#StC" facs="#f023_z015" hand="#comp" place="nc"><hi rend="italic">b</hi></add><del change="#StC" facs="#f023_z015" hand="#Wilde"><hi rend="italic">B</hi></del><hi rend="italic">eauty.</hi> In this they <lb/>were perfectly right. Art herself is<lb/>simply a form of exaggeration<del change="#StC" facs="#f023_z021" hand="#comp">,</del><add change="#StC" facs="#f023_z021" hand="#comp" place="nc">;</add> and <lb/>selection, which is the very spirit of <add change="#StC" facs="#f023_z022" hand="#comp" place="nc">a</add><del change="#StC" facs="#f023_z022" hand="#comp">A</del>rt,<lb/> is nothing more than an intensified mode <lb/>of over-emphasis."</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>