<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio08_diplo"><body><div change="#StB" n="8" type="r"><sp who="#V."><p><pb facs="#f009"/><milestone facs="#f009_z000" n="8" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>rich rhythmic utterances, and in<lb/> neither case will the casual inspiration<lb/> of the moment suffice. Here, as<lb/> elsewhere, practice must precede<lb/> perfection. But in modern days while<lb/> the fashion of <del change="#StBa" facs="#f009_z001" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">reading </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f009_z002" hand="#Wilde" place="above">writing </add>poetry has<lb/> become far too common, and should, if<lb/> possible be discouraged, the fashion<lb/> of lying has almost fallen into<lb/> disrepute. Many a young man<lb/> starts in life with a natural gift<lb/> <del change="#StAb" facs="#f009_z011" hand="#Wilde">of </del><add change="#StB" facs="#f009_z011" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">for</add> exaggeration which, if nurtured<lb/> in congenial and sympathetic surroundings<add change="#StB" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">,</add><lb/> or by the imitation of the best models,<lb/> might grow into something really<lb/> <milestone n="nc_38"/>great and wonderful. But, as a<lb/> rule, he comes to nothing. He either <lb/>falls into careless habits of accuracy...." <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#C.">
					<p><hi change="#StB" rend="underline">Cyril</hi>. My dear Vivian!</p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><hi change="#StB" rend="underline">Vivian</hi>. Please dont interrupt in the<lb/> middle of a sentence. "He either<lb/> falls into careless habits of accuracy,<lb/> or takes to frequenting the society of<lb/> the aged and the well-informed. Both<lb/> things are equally fatal to his<lb/> imagination, as indeed they would be<lb/><milestone facs="#f009_z009" unit="caret"/> <add change="#StBa" facs="#f009_z008" hand="#Wilde" place="margin above" rend="caret">fatal </add>to the imagination of anybody, and in <lb/>a short time he develops a<milestone n="intentions_9"/>morbid<lb/> and unhealthy faculty of truth-telling,<lb/> begins to verify all statements made<lb/> in his presence, has no hesitation in</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>