<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio27_intentions1891">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="27" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f028"/><milestone facs="#f028_z000" n="27" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>Benvenuto Cellini; in the memoirs of <lb/>Casanuova; in Defoe's <hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic">History of the</hi><lb/><hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic"> Plague</hi>; in Boswell's <hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Life of Johnson</hi>;<lb/> in Napoleon's despatches, and in <lb/>the works of our own Carlyle, whose<lb/> <hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic">French Revolution</hi> is one of the most <lb/>fascinating historical <del change="#StD" facs="#f028_z004" hand="#Wilde">romances </del><add change="#StD" facs="#f028_z004" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">novels </add>ever <lb/>written, facts are either kept in their<lb/> proper subordinate position, or else<lb/> entirely excluded on the general ground<lb/> of dulness. Now<add change="#StD" hand="#comp" place="intentions">,</add> everything is changed. <lb/>Facts are not merely finding a footing<lb/> in <add change="#StD" facs="#f028_z007" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">H</add><del change="#StD" facs="#f028_z007" hand="#Wilde">h</del>istory, but they are usurping<lb/> the domain of Fancy, and have invaded<lb/> the kingdom of Romance. Their chilling <lb/>touch is over everything. They are <lb/>vulgarising mankind. The <del change="#StD" facs="#f028_z011" hand="#Wilde">dull </del><add change="#StD" facs="#f028_z011" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">crude </add><lb/>commercial<milestone n="intentions_23"/>ism of America, its materialising<lb/> spirit, its indifference to the poetical<lb/> side of things, and its lack of imagination <lb/>and of high unattainable ideals, are <lb/>entirely due to that country having adopted<lb/> for its national hero<del change="#StD" facs="#f028_z013">,</del> a man, who<add change="#StD" place="intentions">,</add> <lb/>according to his own confession, was <lb/>incapable of telling a lie, and it is <lb/>not too much to say that the story of<lb/> George Washington and the cherry-tree <lb/>has done more harm, and in a shorter <lb/>space of time, than any other moral tale<lb/> in the whole of literature.<add change="#StD" place="intentions">"</add><del change="#StD" hand="#comp">'</del> <lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#C.">
					<p><hi change="#StB" facs="#f028_z001" rend="underline">C.</hi><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">yril.</hi></add>My dear boy!</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>