<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f027_intentions1891"><body><div change="#StB" n="26" type="r"><sp who="#V."><p><pb facs="#f027"/><milestone facs="#f027_z000" n="26" unit="folio_number"/><lb/><del change="#StD" facs="#f027_z001" hand="#Wilde">me </del><add change="#StD" facs="#f027_z001" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">us</add>,'You Christians are so occupied in<lb/> misinterpreting the fourth commandment<lb/> that you have never thought of making an<lb/> artistic application of the second.' He <lb/>was perfectly<milestone n="intentions_22"/>right, and the whole truth <lb/>of the matter is this: <add change="#StD" place="intentions">T</add><del change="#StD"><hi change="#StC" rend="italic">t</hi></del>he proper school to learn art in is not Life but <lb/> Art<hi change="#StC" rend="italic">.</hi><add change="#StD" place="intentions">"</add><del change="#StD" hand="#comp">'</del><lb/><note facs="#f027_z004" rend="pencil">typesetter's signature: Young. Bracket signaling either new paragraph or beginning of new typesetter's section.</note></p>
					<p><milestone facs="#f027_z004" unit="bracket"/>And now let me read you a passage<lb/> which<del change="#StD" facs="#f027_z005" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke"> should have come before this. It </del><lb/><del change="#StD" facs="#f027_z006" hand="#Wilde">deals with the commonplace character of our literature </del><add change="#StD" facs="#f027_z006" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">seems to me to settle the question very completely</add>:--<lb/></p>
					<p><add change="#StD" place="intentions">"</add><del change="#StD" hand="#comp">'</del>It was not always thus. We need <lb/>not say anything about the poets, for they, <lb/>with the unfortunate exception of Mr<del change="#StD" hand="#comp">.</del><lb/>Wordsworth, <milestone n="nc_45"/>have <del change="#StD" facs="#f027_z007" hand="#Wilde">always </del>been <add change="#StD" facs="#f027_z007" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">really </add>faithful to <lb/>their high mission, and are universally <lb/>recognised as being absolutely unreliable.<lb/> But in the works of Herodotus, who, in <lb/>spite of the shallow and ungenerous <lb/>attempts of modern sciolists to verify<lb/> his history, may justly be called the <add change="#StD" facs="#f027_z012" hand="#comp" place="intentions">'</add><del change="#StD" facs="#f027_z012" hand="#comp">"</del>Father of Lies;<add change="#StD" facs="#f027_z012" hand="#comp" place="intentions">'</add><del change="#StD" facs="#f027_z012" hand="#comp">"</del> in the published speeches <lb/>of Cicero and the biographies of Suetonius;<lb/> in Tacitus at his best; in Pliny's <hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Natural</hi><lb/><hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic"> History</hi>; in Hanno's <hi change="#StC" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Periplus</hi>; in all <lb/>the early chronicles; in the Lives of the <lb/>Saints; in Froissart and Sir Thomas <lb/>Mallory; in the travels of Marco Polo;<lb/> in Olaus Magnus, and Aldrovandus,<lb/> and Conrad Lycosthenes, with his <lb/>magnificent <hi rend="italic">Prodigiorum et Ostentorum</hi><lb/><hi rend="italic"> Chronicon</hi>; in the autobiography of</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>