<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio10_nc">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="10" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f011"/><milestone facs="#f010_z000" n="10" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>James writes fiction as if it was <lb/>a painful duty, and wastes upon<lb/> mean motives and imperceptible '<q>points<lb/> of view</q>' his neat literary style, his felicitous phrases, his<lb/> swift and <add change="#StB" facs="#f011_z003" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">caustic </add><lb/>satire.<lb/> <add>Mr</add><lb/><lb/><note>Journalist, biographer, and friend of "one of Wilde's favourite poets, Dante Gabriel Rossetti," Wilde was (reportedly) critical of his Recollections of Dante Gabriel Rossetti immediately following the poets death, and scathingly critiqued his biography of Samuel Taylor Coleredge in a review (Guy 367).</note><lb/><lb/><lb/><lb/><lb/><note>James Payn, prolific mid-nineteenth century journalist, poet, essayist, and novelist.</note><lb/><lb/><note>Scottish writer of what, as Guy explains, was "disparanglinly referred to as the Kailyard (or cabbage-patch) School" (368). Also a pun on the myth of Phaeton.</note><lb/><lb/><note>Per the Clarck Art Museum: "Chromolithography is a term used for color lithographs characterized by saturated, high-gloss color, usually covering the entire sheet. Although color lithography and chromolithography are made by the same technique, their visual results—and uses—contrast greatly. Chromolithographs, known familiarly as “chromos,” were typically associated with popular art and decorative materials: trade cards, children’s books, and reproductive prints of paintings. As mass-produced products, chromolithographs were printed widely to meet consumer demand. While this made artistic images available—and affordable—to many, these works were perceived without the aura of exclusivity or creativity of fine-art color lithographs." Wilde once used the term to disparaginly describe the methoeds of Scottish novelists (Reviews 163; Guy 368). The following passage about local colour" closely echoes his earlier critique of Scottish novelists, and may be yet another instance of his "Self-plagiarism," or adaptive revision of his other works, demonstrating a self-reflexive dimension to his "creative ecology" (Van Hulle). https://www.clarkart.edu/microsites/hue-cry/chromolithography#:~:text=Chromolithography%20is%20a%20term%20used,%E2%80%94and%20uses%E2%80%94contrast%20greatly.</note><lb/> Mrs. Oliphant prattles pleasantly<note>Scottish novelist Margaret Oliphant</note><lb/> about curates, lawn-tennis parties, <lb/>domesticity, and other wearisome things.<lb/>Mr. Marion Crawford has immolated<note>As Guy notes, "a popular and prolific ex-patriot American author and historian" (368).</note><lb/> himself upon the altar of local<lb/> colour. He is like the lady in the<lb/> French comedy who keeps talking<lb/> about <del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z005" hand="#comp">"</del><add change="#StC" facs="#f011_z005" hand="#comp" place="nc">'</add><hi change="#StB" facs="#f011_z005" rend="underline">le beau ciel d'Italie</hi>.<del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z005" hand="#comp">"</del><add change="#StC" facs="#f011_z005" hand="#comp" place="nc">'</add> Besides, he<lb/> has fallen into a bad habit of uttering<lb/> moral platitudes. At times he<lb/> is always edifying. <del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z006" hand="#comp">'</del><hi change="#StC" facs="#f011_z006" rend="italic">Robert Elsmere</hi><del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z006" hand="#comp">'</del> is<note>Wilde's revised criticisms of the Mary Ward's novel occur both before and after his initial composition of the first version of Dorian Gray in 1890. As Andrew Elfenbein has persausively argued in "On the Discrimination of Influences” (MLQ, esp. 496-505), Wilde's novel simultaneously mocks and adopts certain textual features of teh extremely popular novel, illustrating the complex "influece" of reading on composition. Wilde's iterative passes at this part of the essay not only suggests a clear preoccupation with novel in fashion that materially substantiates Elfenbein's claims, but also, as an illustration of Van Hulle's notion of creative concurrence, materializes in a confluence of creative activity the social, dialectic nature of writing (and literary influence, as Elfenbein argues).</note><lb/> of course, a masterpiece<del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z007" hand="#comp">,</del><add change="#StC" hand="#comp" place="nc">—</add>a masterpiece<lb/> of the <del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z008" hand="#comp">"</del><add change="#StC" facs="#f011_z008" hand="#comp" place="nc">'</add>genre ennuyeux,<del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z008" hand="#comp">"</del><add change="#StC" facs="#f011_z008" hand="#comp" place="nc">'</add> the <del change="#StBa" facs="#f011_z009" hand="#Wilde" rend="multi-stroke">only </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f011_z010" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="no_caret">one </add>form<lb/> of literature that English people<lb/> seem to thoroughly enjoy. <note>"A meat-tea was a more substantial meal takien later in the day, and is used by W to indicate the indicate the eating habits of the lower classes or of those who disregarded, or wer ignorant of, the rules of etiquette which governed polite society. . .Nonconformist was a broad term in the 19th century to refer to a variety of of Protestant sects whcih defined themselves in opposition to the teachings of the Anglican or established chruch; in Culture and Anarchy (1869) Matthew Arnold identified nonconformiism with pronvincialism and culgarity, and criticized its partisan tendencies as culturally divisive.</note>Indeed it is<lb/> only in England that such a book <del change="#StBa" facs="#f011_z011" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">would </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f011_z012" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="no_caret">could </add><add change="#StB" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">be </add>possible .<note facs="#f011_z017">This passage underwent revisions in in each iteration of the essay. Wilde first expanded the Berg version, introducing the "friend" framework, when drafting this fair-copy version. Then, when restoring the ommitted passage for Intentions, he changed the language to include Cyril: "mine" was changed to "ours" and me to "us". The friends enjoyment of the story, and any "praise" given to it, were also removed. "he liked it because" was excised, and already revised "praise we can give to it" ("thing that can be said to its favour" upon initial inscription") was changed to "and we can quite believe it." The passage was relocated to before "Indeed" and the sentence "England is the home of lost ideas" was added after the "produced" (altered from "possible")</note> . <del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z017" hand="#comp">A thoughtful<lb/> young friend of mine once told me<lb/> that he liked it because it reminded<lb/> him of the sort of conversation that<lb/> goes on at a meat-tea in the house<lb/> of a serious Nonconformist family,<lb/> and this is perhaps the highest thing<lb/></del><del change="#StBa" facs="#f011_z014 #f011_z015" hand="#Wilde" rend="multi-stroke">that can be said in its favour.</del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f011_z016" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="no_caret"><del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z017" hand="#comp">praise that we can give to it.</del></add>As<lb/> for that great and daily<del change="#StC" facs="#f011_z018" hand="#comp">-</del>increasing<lb/> school of novelists for whom the<lb/> sun always rises in the East-End, the<lb/> only thing that can be said about them</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>