<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f046_intentions1891">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="45" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f046"/><milestone facs="#f046_z000" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>artist ever sees things as they really are. If<lb/> he did, he would<milestone n="intentions_38"/> cease to be an artist. Take<lb/> an example from our own day. <lb/> I know that you are fond of Japanese<lb/> things. Now, do you really imagine that the<lb/> Japanese people, as they are presented to us in <lb/>art, have any existence? If you do,<lb/> you have never understood Japanese art at all. <lb/>The Japanese people are the deliberate <add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z006" hand="#Wilde" place="nc">self-conscious </add>creation <lb/>of certain <add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z007" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">individual </add>artists. . If you set a picture by<lb/> Hokusia, or Hokkei, or any of the great<lb/> native painters, beside a real Japanese<lb/> gentleman or lady,<del change="#StD" facs="#f046_z008" hand="#Wilde"> or beside a photograph of a </del><lb/><del change="#StD" facs="#f046_z009" hand="#Wilde">Japanese gentleman or lady,</del> you will see that <lb/>there is not the slightest resemblance between<lb/> them. The actual people who live in Japan<lb/> are not unlike the general run of English<lb/> people; that is to say, they are extremely commonplace,<lb/> andhave nothing curious or extraordinary about<lb/> them. In fact, the whole of Japan is a pure<lb/> invention. There is no such country, there are<lb/> no such people. One of our most charming<lb/> painters <del change="#StD" facs="#f046_z015" hand="#Wilde">whose tiny full-length portaits of<lb/>children are so beautiful and so powerful that <lb/>he should be <milestone facs="#f046_z016" unit="enclosure"/>called the Velasquez to the Court of <lb/>Lilliput </del><add change="#StD">went recently to the </add><del change="#StD" facs="#f046_z015" hand="#Wilde">Japan </del><add change="#StD">Land of the Chrysanthemum </add>in the foolish hope<lb/> of seeing the Japanese. All he saw, all he<lb/> had the chance of painting, were a few lanterns<lb/> and some fans. He was quite unable to discover the<lb/> inhabitants, as<del change="#StD" facs="#f046_z017" hand="#Wilde"> anyone could see who visits</del> his <lb/>delightful exhibition at Messrs. Dowdeswell's Gallery showed only too well. He did<lb/> not know that the Japanese people are, as I <lb/>have said, simply a mode of style, a<del change="#StD" facs="#f046_z019" hand="#Wilde"> whimsical </del><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z019" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">n exquisite</add> <lb/>fancy of art. <lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">And so, if you desire to see a Japanese effect, </add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">you will not behave like a tourist and go to Tokio.</add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> On the contrary, you will stay at home, and steep </add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">yourself in the work of certain Japanese artists,</add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> and then, when you have absorbed the spirit of</add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> their style, and caught their imaginative manner</add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> of vision, you will go some afternoon and sit in the</add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> Park, or stroll down Piccadilly, and </add><milestone n="intentions_39"/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">if you cannot </add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">see an absolutely Japanese effect there, you </add><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f046_z020" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">will not see it anywhere.</add></p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>