<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f050_diplo"><body><div change="#StB" n="49" type="r"><sp who="#V."><p><pb facs="#f050"/><milestone facs="#f050_z000"/><lb/>for the Church I cannot conceive <lb/>anything better for the <del change="#StBa" facs="#f050_z008" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">art of a </del><lb/>culture of a country than the presence<lb/> in it of a body of men whose duty it <lb/>is to believe in the supernatural, to<lb/> perform daily miracles, and to keep<lb/> alive that mythopoeic faculty which is <lb/>so essential for the imagination. But<lb/> in the English Church a man succeeds <lb/>not <del change="#StBa" facs="#f050_z010" hand="#Wilde" rend="multi-stroke">in proper </del>through his capacity for<lb/> belief but through his capacity for<lb/> disbelief. Ours is the only Church where <lb/>the sceptic stands at the altar, and <lb/>where St. Thomas is regarded as the <lb/>ideal apostle. Many a worthy clergyman <lb/>who passes his life in admirable works <lb/>of kindly charity lives and dies <lb/>unnoticed and unknown; but it is sufficient <lb/>for some shallow uneducated passman <lb/>out of either University to get up in <lb/>his pulpit and express his doubts <lb/>about Noah's ark, or Balaam's ass, or <lb/>Jonah and the whale, for <del change="#StBa" facs="#f050_z011" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">the whole </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f050_z012" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="no_caret">half </add>of <lb/>London to flock to hear him, and to<lb/> sit open-mouthed in rapt admiration<lb/> at his superb<milestone n="intentions_41"/> intellect. The growth of<lb/> common sense in the English Church is<lb/> a thing very much to be regretted. It is<lb/> really a degrading concession to a low form<lb/> of realism. However, I must read the end<lb/> of my article.<note facs="#f050_z001" rend="pencil">Typesetter's Signature: Deely</note><lb/></p>
					<p><milestone facs="#f050_z002" unit="bracket"/> <note facs="#f050_z003">Passage pulled from deleted content on <ref target="#f049_z005">48A</ref></note> <add change="#StB" facs="#f050_z003" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">"</add> <add change="#StB" facs="#f050_z003" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">What we have to do, what at any rate it is our duty<lb/></add> <add change="#StB" facs="#f050_z004" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">to do,</add> <add change="#StB" facs="#f050_z003" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">is to revive this old</add> <del change="#StAb" facs="#f050_z005" hand="#Wilde">habit </del><add change="#StB" facs="#f050_z003" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">art of L</add> <add change="#StB" facs="#f050_z003" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">ying. Much<lb/> of course may be done</add> <add change="#StB" facs="#f050_z003" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">in the way of educating<lb/> the public</add> <add change="#StB" facs="#f050_z003" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">by amateurs in the domestic circle,<lb/> at literary lunches, and at</add></p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>