<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio18_intentions1894"><body><div change="#StB" n="18" type="r"><sp who="#V."><p><pb facs="#f019"/><milestone facs="#f019_z000" n="18"/><lb/>a vital part of the environment<lb/> in which we live, it is <lb/> outside the proper sphere of Art. To Art's<lb/> subject-<milestone n="intentions_16"/>matter we should be more or<lb/> less indifferent. We should, at any<lb/> rate, have no preferences, no prejudices,<lb/> no partizan feeling of any kind. It is<lb/> exactly because Hecuba is nothing to<lb/> us that her sorrows are such an<lb/> admirable motive for a tragedy. I do<lb/> not know anything in the whole<lb/> history of literature sadder than the<lb/> artistic career<milestone facs="#f019_z006" unit="caret"/> of Charles Reade. He wrote one<lb/> beautiful book, <hi change="#StC" facs="#f019_z007" hand="#comp" rend="italic">The Cloister and the</hi><lb/><hi change="#StC" facs="#f019_z007" hand="#comp" rend="italic"> Hearth</hi>, a book as much above <hi change="#StC" facs="#f019_z008" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Romola</hi><lb/> as <hi change="#StC" facs="#f019_z009" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Romola</hi> is above <hi change="#StC" facs="#f019_z010" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Daniel Deronda</hi>,<lb/> and wasted the <milestone/>rest of his life in a foolish<lb/> attempt to be modern, to draw public<lb/> attention to the state of our convict<lb/> prisons, and the management of our private<lb/> lunatic asylums. Charles Dickens was depressing enough in all conscience when<lb/> he tried to arouse our sympathy for<lb/> the victims of the poor-law administration; <lb/>but Charles Reade, an artist, a scholar, <milestone facs="#f019_z016" unit="enclosure"/>a man<lb/> with a<milestone facs="#f019_z017" unit="caret"/> true sense of beauty, raging and<lb/> roaring over the abuses of contemporary <lb/>life like a common pamphleteer or<lb/> a sensational journalist, is really a<lb/> sight for the angels to weep over.<lb/> Believe me, my dear Cyril, modernity of<lb/> form<milestone n="nc_42"/> and modernity of subject-matter are</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>