<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio45_nc">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="45" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f046"/><milestone facs="#f046_z000" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>artist ever sees things as they really are. If<lb/> he did, he would<milestone n="intentions_38"/> cease to be an artist. Take<lb/> an example from our own day. <del change="#StBa" facs="#f046_z001" hand="#Wilde" rend="multi-stroke">Surely you </del><lb/><del change="#StBa" facs="#f046_z002" hand="#Wilde" rend="multi-stroke">don't</del> I know that you are fond of Japanese<lb/> things. Now, do you really imagine that the<lb/> Japanese people, <del change="#StC" facs="#f046_z003 #f046_z004">as we know them through the medium of</del> <add change="#StC" facs="#f046_z003 #f046_z004" place="nc">as they are presented to us in</add> <lb/>art, have any existence? If you do,<lb/> you have never understood Japanese art at all. <lb/>The Japanese people are the deliberate <del change="#StBa" facs="#f046_z005" hand="#Wilde" rend="single-stroke">invention </del><add change="#StBa" facs="#f046_z006" hand="#Wilde" place="above" rend="no_caret">creation </add><lb/>of certain artists. . If you set a picture by<lb/> Hokusia, or Hokkei, or any of the great<lb/> native painters, beside a real Japanese<lb/> gentleman or lady, or beside a photograph of a <lb/>Japanese gentleman or lady, you will see that <lb/>there is not the slightest resemblance between<lb/> them. The actual people who live in Japan<lb/> are not unlike the general run of English<lb/> people<add change="#StC" facs="#f046_z011" hand="#comp" place="nc">;</add><del change="#StC" facs="#f046_z011" hand="#comp">,</del> that is to say<add change="#StC" hand="#comp" place="nc">,</add> they are extremely commonplace,<lb/> and<add change="#StB" facs="#f046_z013" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">have nothing curious<del change="#StC" facs="#f046_z012" hand="#comp">,</del> or extraordinary</add> about<lb/> them. In fact<add change="#StC" hand="#comp" place="nc">,</add> the whole of Japan is a pure<lb/> invention. There is no such country, there are<lb/> no such people. One of our most charming<lb/> painters<del change="#StC" facs="#f046_z014" hand="#comp">,</del> whose tiny full-length portaits of<lb/>children are so beautiful and so powerful that <lb/>he should be <milestone facs="#f046_z016" unit="enclosure"/><add change="#StBa" facs="#f046_z016" hand="#Wilde" place="above inline" rend="caret_enclosure">called </add>the Velasquez to the Court of <lb/>Lilliput Japan in the <add change="#StC" facs="#f046_z015" place="nc">foolish </add>hope<del change="#StC" facs="#f046_z015">s</del><lb/> of seeing the Japanese. All he saw, all he<lb/> had the chance of painting, were a few lanterns<lb/> and some fans. He was quite unable to discover the<lb/> inhabitants, as anyone could see who visits his <lb/>delightful exhibition at <add change="#StC" facs="#f046_z018" hand="#Wilde" place="nc">Messrs. </add>Dowdeswell<add change="#StC" facs="#f046_z018" hand="#Wilde" place="nc">'s Gallery</add> <add change="#StC" facs="#f046_z018" hand="#Wilde" place="nc">showed only too well.</add> He did<lb/> not know that the Japanese people are, as I <lb/>have said, simply a mode of style, a whimsical <lb/>fancy of art. <lb/><lb/><lb/><lb/><lb/><lb/><lb/><lb/><milestone n="intentions_39"/><lb/><lb/></p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>