<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="f008_nc"><body><div change="#StB" n="7" type="r"><sp who="#V."><p><pb facs="#f008"/><milestone facs="#f008_z000" n="7" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>into which he peers with his microscope.<lb/> He is to be found at the Librairie<note>As Guy notes, Wilde presumably means the national library, the Bilotheque Nationale, in Paris.</note><lb/> Nationale, or at the British Museum,<note>Schroeder argues that this passage was the basis for a passage in Max Beerbom's Parody of 1893 parody "Oscar Wilde." See Anglo-American Times, 25 March 1893 and Schroeder 28.</note><lb/> shamelessly reading up his subject. He<lb/> has not even the courage of other people's <note>Guy notes that this may have been an allusion to Whistler, who had previously accused Wilde of plagiarism and would later accuse him of plagiarizing "The Decay of Lying" from his Lectures. This prompted a series of additions to the Intentions edition of "The Decay of Lying" directed at Whilster.</note><lb/> ideas<add change="#StC" hand="#comp" place="nc">,</add> but insists on going directly to<lb/> life for everything, and ultimately<add change="#StC" hand="#comp" place="nc">,</add><lb/> between <add change="#StC" facs="#f008_z001" hand="#comp" place="nc">e</add><del change="#StC" facs="#f008_z001" hand="#comp">E</del>ncyclopædias and personal<lb/> experience<add change="#StC" hand="#comp" place="nc">,</add> he comes to the ground,<lb/> having drawn his types from the family<lb/> circle or from the weekly washerwoman,<note>Possible allusion to Zola's L'Assomoir</note><lb/> and having acquired an amount of<lb/> useful information from which never,<lb/> even in his most meditative moments,<lb/> can he thoroughly free himself.<del change="#StC">" </del><lb/></p>
					<p><add change="#StC" facs="#f008_z003" hand="#comp" place="nc">'</add><del change="#StC" facs="#f008_z003" hand="#comp">"</del>The loss that results to literature<lb/> in general from<milestone n="intentions_8"/>this false ideal of <lb/>our time can hardly be overestimated.<lb/> People have a careless way of talking<lb/> about a 'born liar,' just as they talk<lb/> about a 'born poet.' But in both<lb/> cases they are wrong. Lying and<lb/> <add change="#StC" facs="#f008_z004" hand="#comp" place="nc">p</add><del change="#StC" facs="#f008_z004" hand="#comp">P</del>oetry are arts<del change="#StC" facs="#f008_z005" hand="#StCb">,</del><add change="#StC" facs="#f008_z005" hand="#comp" place="nc">--</add>arts, as Plato saw<add change="#StC" hand="#comp" place="nc">,</add><lb/> not unconnected with each other<del change="#StC" facs="#f008_z006" hand="#StCb">,</del><add change="#StC" facs="#f008_z006" hand="#comp" place="nc">--</add>and<lb/> they require the most careful study,<note>Reference to The Republic, Book 10, 595 ff. (Guy 366). One can trace the connection between lying and poetry to "poiesis," derived from the Greek "ποιεῖν" or "to make." I.e, both are acts of creating something wholly new, which Wilde continues to position in opposition to realism or naturalism's mimitec attempts at REpresentation. See also the addition to Folio 53.</note><lb/> the most disinterested devotion. Indeed,<lb/> they have their technique, just as the<lb/> <add change="#StB" facs="#f008_z008" hand="#Wilde" place="inline">more material arts of</add> painting and<lb/> sculpture have, their subtle secrets of<lb/> form and colour, their craft-mysteries,<lb/> their deliberate artistic methods. As<lb/> one knows the poet by his fine music,<lb/> so one can recognise the <add change="#StC" facs="#f008_z007" hand="#comp" place="nc">l</add><del change="#StC" facs="#f008_z007" hand="#comp">L</del>iar by his</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>