<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio12_intentions1891">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="12" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f013"/><milestone facs="#f013_z001" n="12" unit="folio_number"/><lb/><add change="#StD" facs="#f013_z000" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">Tartuffe on being exposed </add><del change="#StD" facs="#f013_z000" hand="#Wilde">Caliban on seeing his own face in a</del><lb/><del change="#StD" facs="#f013_z000" hand="#Wilde"> glass </del>. But from the standpoint of<lb/>art, what can be said in favour<lb/> of the author of <hi change="#StC" facs="#f013_z003" hand="#comp" rend="italic">L'Assommoir</hi>, <hi change="#StC" facs="#f013_z003" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Nana</hi>, and <hi change="#StC" facs="#f013_z003" hand="#comp" rend="italic">Pot- Bouille</hi>? Nothing. Mr Ruskin<lb/> once described the characters in George<lb/> Eliot's novels as being like<lb/> <q facs="#f013_z004">the<lb/> sweepings of a Pentonville omnibus</q>,<note>Fiction – Fair and Foul V’, Nineteenth Century, 10 (1881), 521</note> but<lb/> M. Zola's characters are much worse.<lb/> They have their dreary vices, and their drearier<lb/> virtues. The record of their lives is absolutely<lb/> without interest. Who cares what happens to<lb/> them? In literature we require distinction, charm,<lb/> beauty, and imaginative power. We don't want to<lb/> be harrowed and disgusted with an account of<lb/> the doings of the lower orders. M. Daudet is<lb/> better. He has <del change="#StD" facs="#f013_z007" hand="#Wilde"><hi rend="italic">espirit </hi></del><add change="#StD" facs="#f013_z007" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">wit</add>,<milestone n="intentions_12"/> a light touch, and an<lb/> amusing style. But he has lately committed<lb/> literary suicide. Nobody can possibly care for<lb/> Delobelle with his <del change="#StD">"</del><add change="#StD" place="intentions">'</add><hi change="#StB" facs="#f013_z010" rend="underline">Il faut lutter pour l'art</hi>,<del change="#StD">"</del><add change="#StD" place="intentions">'</add><lb/> or for Valmajour with his eternal refrain about<lb/> the nightingale, or for the poet in <hi rend="italic">Jack</hi> with his <del change="#StD">"</del><add change="#StD" place="intentions">'</add><hi facs="#f013_z012" rend="underline">mots cruels,</hi><del change="#StD">"</del><add change="#StD" place="intentions">'</add>' now that we have learned from <hi rend="italic">Vingt Ans de ma Vie littéraire</hi> that these characters<lb/> weretaken directly from life. To <del change="#StD" facs="#f013_z015" hand="#Wilde">me </del><add change="#StD" facs="#f013_z015" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">us </add>they seem to<lb/> have suddenly lost all their vitality, all the<lb/> few qualities they ever possessed. The only real<lb/> people are the people who never existed; and if<lb/> a novelist is base enough to go to life for<lb/> his personages, he should at least pretend <lb/>that they are creations, and not boast of them<lb/> as copies. <add change="#StD" facs="#f013_z019" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">The justification of a character in a novel is not that other persons are what they are, but that the author is what he is. Otherwise the novel is not a work of art. </add>As for M. Paul Bourget,</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>