<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="folio02_intentions1891">
		<body>
			<div change="#StB" n="2" type="r">
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><pb facs="#f003"/><milestone facs="#f003_z000" n="2" unit="folio_number"/><lb/>I look at a landscape I cannot<lb/> help seeing all its defects. It is fortunate for us, <milestone facs="#f003_z002"/>however, that Nature is so<lb/> imperfect, as otherwise we should<lb/> have had no art <milestone facs="#f003_z004" unit="enclosure"/>at all. Art is our spirited<lb/> protest, our<milestone facs="#f003_z007" unit="caret"/> gallant attempt to teach Nature<lb/> her proper place. As for the infinite<lb/> variety of Nature, that is a <milestone n="Intentions_4"/> pure<lb/> myth.<note>Schroeder argues that this is both a challenging of John Addington Symonds 1887 assertion that "t will never match the infinite variety and subtlety of nature; no drawing or painting will equal the primary beauties of the living model' (The Model', Fortnightly Review , vol.42, (Dec. 1887), p 859) and an allusiton to Shakespeare's Antony and Cleopatra, II.ii.239 f.</note> It is not to be found in<lb/> Nature herself <del change="#StD" facs="#f003_z010" hand="#Wilde">but,</del><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">. It resides</add> in the imagination,<lb/> or fancy, or <milestone facs="#f003_z013" unit="caret"/> cultivated blindness of the man who<lb/> looks at her.<lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#C.">
					<p><hi rend="underline">C</hi><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">yril</hi></add><hi rend="underline">.</hi> Well, you need not look at<lb/> the landscape. You can lie on<lb/> the grass and smoke and talk.<lb/></p>
				</sp>
				<sp who="#V.">
					<p><hi change="#StC" facs="#f003_z015" hand="#comp" rend="underline">V</hi><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"><hi rend="italic">ivian</hi></add><hi change="#StC" facs="#f003_z015" hand="#comp" rend="underline">. </hi>But <add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">N</add><del change="#StD" hand="#Wilde">n</del>ature is so uncomfortable.<lb/> Grass is hard and lumpy and damp,<lb/> and full of dreadful black insects. Why, even <del change="#StD" hand="#Wilde">Maple</del><note>Large commercial furniture firm, located at Tottenham Court Road.</note><lb/> <add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">Morris'</add><note>Guy identifies the reference as an allusion to "the simple, inexpensive, black-stained rush-bottomed 'Sussex' chairs" sold by Morris &amp; Co., "a firm established by poet, painter, and designer William Morris" (362).</note><add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions"> poorest workman could </add><del change="#StD" hand="#Wilde">can </del>make you a more comfortable<lb/> seat than the whole of <add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">N</add><del change="#StD" hand="#Wilde">n</del>ature can. Nature pales before the <del change="#StD" hand="#Wilde">Tottenham Court Road.</del> <add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">furniture of "the street which from Oxford has borrowed its name,” as the poet you love so much once vilely phrased it.</add><note>The addition</note> I<lb/> don't complain. If <add change="#StD" hand="#Wilde" place="intentions">N</add><del change="#StD" hand="#Wilde">n</del>ature had been comfortable, mankind would never have<lb/> invented architecture, and I prefer houses to the open air. In a house<lb/> we all feel of the proper proportions.<lb/> Everything is subordinated to us,<lb/> fashioned for our use and <milestone facs="#f003_z019" unit="caret"/>our pleasure.</p>
				</sp>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>